idrc.ca 2019-05-26

# Privacy Notice | IDRC - International Development Research Centre

IDRC respects the privacy concerns of users of this website.

This Privacy Notice explains how personal information that is collected from and about the visitors to IDRC’s website is handled.

All personal information held or collected by IDRC is protected under Canada’s _  Privacy Act_. 

## Information automatically collected from all users

Software programs automatically receive and temporarily store information in our web server logs. Some of the information automatically collected by our server when you browse our website includes:

  * the network location and the Internet Protocol (IP) address of the device you used to contact our website;
  * the type of browser you used;
  * the date and time you accessed the site; and
  * the pages you access and the documents you download.

## Cookies

This website uses cookies to store user preferences (for example, language preference). Cookies allow us to capture information about how site visitors use our website – where they come from, what pages they visit and how much time they spent visiting. This information is compiled, analysed and used to enhance the user online experience at this website and to provide IDRC with information such as the number of visitors to the website.

A cookie is a small file containing a string of characters that is sent to your computer when you visit a website. When you visit the website again within a specified period of time, the cookie allows that site to recognize you as a return visitor. You can reset your browser to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent.

## Web Analytics

Web analytics is the collection, measurement, analysis and reporting of website data for purposes of understanding visitor behaviour and improving the website’s usefulness to its users.

This website uses Google Analytics  to provide web analytics services. IDRC uses the visitor information captured by Google Analytics to improve the user experience of its website and to ensure the content on its website is presented in a manner that makes it easy for site visitors to find and act upon. 

## Google Analytics

Google Analytics uses both session cookies and persistent first-party cookies to track how our visitors use this site. Session cookies have no set expiration date. They are deleted from memory when the browser closes. Persistent cookies have a defined expiration date. The browser will only delete them when they expire (typically after six months).

Google Analytics collects standard Internet log information to track visitor behaviour information as follows:

  * Audience related data, including the city and country of origin, language preference, frequency of visits, all a visitor’s activity during a single session, and operating system, service provider and device used to access the site. 
  * Traffic source data, including the ways visitors arrive at [www.idrc.ca ](http://www.idrc.ca%20/)(for example search engines, referrals from other sites, marketing campaigns, and social media), keywords visitors entered into a search engine and that brought them to our website, and the landing and exit page used by which a visitors enters and leave our site.  
  * Content related data, including measuring user visits and page views to determine the site’s most popular content, technical performance of the site as measured by such elements as average time taken to load a page and server speed, and technical performance broken down further by country and web browser.

The information generated by cookies about your use of this website (including your IP address, truncated to ensure your anonymity) is transmitted to Google. This information is used to compile statistical reports on the website’s activities and enhance the user online experience.

For more information about Google Analytics, please visit [ http://www.google.com/intl/en-ALL/policies/privacy/ ](http://www.google.com/intl/en_ALL/policies/privacy/). Those wishing to opt out of Google Analytics data collection should use the Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on (<https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>).

The data disclosed to Google will be transmitted outside of Canada to other jurisdictions, including the United States.  Data transmitted to other jurisdictions will be subject to the laws of those jurisdictions.  Data transmitted to the United States will be subject to the laws of the United States, including the  _USA Patriot Act_.  

The IP address, and any other personal information including, but not limited to, information in digital markers used in relation to Web analytics, is retained by IDRC for a maximum period of 18 months.

## Newsletters and email alerts

Our newsletters (the IDRC Bulletin, the Funding Alert, and circulars from our Regional Offices use [ **Mailchimp**](https://mailchimp.com/), a third-party application. Sign-up is voluntary and subject to the [ **Terms of Use**](https://mailchimp.com/legal/terms/) for the Mailchimp platform. When you register, your email address is maintained. No other personal information is collected, and your information is only used for the intended purpose of sending you a regular newsletter. You can unsubscribe at any time. 

Please note that this website provides links to other sites that are not covered by this Privacy Notice.
